Remember...
牢记
Nevra, wrap the case up for me.
内芙拉，梳理一下案情
Mehmet Yurtgil, Naimhan Turedi...
穆罕默德·尤特吉尔，纳伊姆汉·图雷迪
The last victim's name was Salih Guden.
最后一位受害者的名字是萨利赫·古登
Three victims. Scratch Tufan. Two of them are from Kambura.
除去图凡之外  三名受害者中有两人来自坎布拉
You've lived in Kambura for a while.
你在坎布拉住过很长一段时间
So all this does have something to do with Kambura.
所以这一切都与坎布拉有关
- It's Nazif! - Nazif?
-我是纳齐夫！-纳齐夫？
Do you know Agah Beyoglu?
你知道阿加·贝尤鲁吗？
The biggest favor you can do for such a sociopath is to talk about him.
你可以为这样的社会变态者做的最大的帮助就是谈论他
The one you chased all the way here... You never saw his face?
你一直在追逐的那个人  没看到他的脸吗？
Someone threw a torch at the house. It flared up...
有人向房子扔了火把
and burned the house down.
把房子烧了
You're talking too much...
你说的太多了
Something might happen to you.
你可能会发生什么事
Is it supposed to be a rabbit?
那是兔子吗？
No. It's a cat.
不，是猫
- Agah, you tired? - No, no, I'm fine.
-阿加，你累吗？-不，不，我没事
I know it was quite a walk, but these sprout only in the morning.
我知道这是很长一段路，但是这些植物只在早晨发芽
You almost missed me. I was just about to leave.
你差点错过，我就要走了
It was really surprising, seeing you standing there.
看到你真是令人惊讶
You haven't changed a bit. You look great.
你一点都没变  看起来很棒
- Neither have you, Seyfi. - Except for getting older, that is.
-你也没变  塞菲  -除了变老
Agah, when I'm your age, I hope to be...
阿加，当我到你这么老的时候，我希望我……
Look over there!
看那边！
There it is.
在那里
See this mushroom?
看到这个蘑菇吗？
This is a death cap.
这是一个毒蘑菇
One bite and you're dead.
一口就死了
It's that poisonous.
这是有毒的
Agah, what is that? What are you doing?
阿加，这是什么？你在做什么？
Where is Umut, Seyfi?
塞菲，乌穆特在哪里？
- The small intestine. It belongs... - There.
-小肠  属于……  -那里
Yes, there.
是的，那里
Where is Umut?
乌穆特在哪里？
- The large intestine.
-大肠  -大肠
The large intestine. It belongs there.
大肠属于那里
- Where's Umut? - Fuck you!
-乌穆特在哪里？-去尼玛！
You've heard about astrology, right?
你听说过占星术吗？
It's a ridiculous idea.
那是个荒谬的行为
Where's Umut?
乌穆特在哪里？
You can't figure out someone's personality from their birth date.
你不能从某人的出生日期就看出他的个性
Let alone their future...
更不用说他们的未来
From their birth date? Impossible.
用出生日期开占卜？真不可思议
You know what works, though?
你知道什么可以吗？
Their birth place.
出生地
Where you're born dictates your personality and your future.
出生地决定了你的个性和未来
Astrology should take birth places into account.
占星术应该考虑出生地
Predictions made on birth places would be more plausible.
考虑到出生地的预测会更合理
In the end, children born in Tripoli,
最终，在的黎波里出生的孩子
Peshawar, or Angola
白沙瓦或安哥拉
will live pretty much identical lives.
将过着几乎相同的生活
And then there's Toronto, Oslo, Tokyo.
然后是多伦多，奥斯陆，东京
Those children, as well.
那些孩子也是一样
Our rural people are well aware of this fact.
我们的农村人民非常了解这一事实
That's why...
这就是为什么
This goes there.
这个在那里
They never ask someone they meet for the first time what their sign is.
人们从来没有问过他们第一次见面的人
They ask them where they're from.
问他们来自哪里
I won't ask you again. Will you talk?
我不会再问了，你说不说？
Wait.
等等
Speak into this.
对着这个说
Speak into this, you got that?
说吧，明白吗？
And then there's the rising sign.
应该有个上升星座
That corresponds to your citizenship.
那对应你的公民身份
What country you're born in.
你出生在哪个国家
That's important, as well.
这也很重要
A Syrian boy born in Syria does not share the same fate
在叙利亚出生的叙利亚男孩的命运
with a French boy born in Syria.
和一个在叙利亚出生的法国男孩不尽相同
My sign is Aleppo. My rising sign is French.
我的星座是阿勒普  我的上升星座是法国
That changes things.
这改变了一切
Or...
或者
My sign is Congo. My rising sign is Belgium.
我的星座是刚果  我的上升星座是比利时
It changes things.
这也改变了一切
And my sign is Kambura.
我的星座是坎布拉
So is my destiny.
命运也是一样
Whatever I've made of myself, I owe it all to being born in Kambura.
不管我做什么，我全都归功于在坎布拉出生
Go on.
去吧
Join your friends.
去找你的朋友吧
There's someone on the loose.
现在有人在外面
He's killed my brothers.
杀了我兄弟
He's shot my people from Kambura.
他在坎布拉枪杀了我的人
He's out there as we speak.
我们讲话时他在外面
And here you are, just standing there.
而你却站在这里
You're going to find him. Not to arrest him, Firuz.
你要找到他，但不要逮捕他，菲鲁兹
He is not to stand trial.
他不会接受审判
You will bring that son of a bitch to me, Firuz.
你把那个疯子交给我，菲鲁兹
I'll hold his trial,
我会审判他的
and I'll pass his judgement.
我会为他做出判决
- Is this a bad time, Cemil? - Come on in, Zuhal.
-现在不方便吗，塞米尔？-什么事，祖哈尔
You have a meeting with
在半小时后你有一个
our Middle Eastern representatives in half an hour.
与中东代表的会议
We should get back to the office.
我们应该回到办公室
What's your sign, Zuhal?
祖哈尔，你的星座是什么？
Capricorn.
摩羯座
But I don't really believe in signs.
但是我真的不相信星座
See? She doesn't believe in them, either.
看吗？她也不相信
Get back to work, and keep me posted.
回去工作，随时向我汇报
What's your sign?
你的星座是什么？
Dragon.
龙
Come visit us again soon, Tolga.
托尔加，不久再来看我们吧
I'd love that. Thank you for your hospitality.
我会的  谢谢你的招待
Goodbye.
再见
My mom's lying.
我妈妈在说谎
She didn't seem like she was lying.
她看起来不像在说谎
Her husband obviously has some problems.
但是她丈夫显然有一些问题
Might he have dreamt it all up?
真的只是做梦吗？
He might have.
有可能
Sir...
长官
You must have realized that my mom and I aren't very close.
你应该知道我和我妈妈关系不是很好
In fact, sometimes, I start doubting that I know her at all.
事实上，有时候我甚至怀疑自己是否认识她
But believe me, I can tell when she's lying.
但是相信我，我能看出她什么时候在说谎
Here's what we're going to do: I need to get back to the bureau.
我们要做的是：我需要回到局
Drop me off at the local precinct. I'll get a car there and go back.
让我在当地分局下车  我去那儿弄辆车回来
Call Sefa and call him over.
打电话给塞法  让他过来
Talk to the locals, see if anyone remembers the fire.
问问当地人，看看是否有人记得大火
- Is that clear? - Yes, sir.
-清楚吗？-是的 长官
Nevra...
内芙拉
If you don't come up with any leads about the fire today,
如果你今天找不出任何有关火灾的线索，
you're going to drop it. Alright?
就不要再找了，好吗？
Neither of us has any time to waste. Is that clear?
我们都没有时间可以浪费了，明白吗？
Yes, sir.
是  长官
Good. Drop me off, and get some rest while you're waiting for Sefa.
好，送我过去，你等着塞法，正好休息一下
Don't need that. You haven't slept, either.
不用了  你不是也没睡觉
I got a good night's sleep sometime last year.
我上次睡好觉是在去年
Let's go. Drop me off.
走吧，送我过去
Say you're sorry first.
先说对不起
Suveyda,
苏薇达
I said some...
我说了一些
stupid things about you.
关于你的谣言
Tell her exactly what you said.
告诉她你到底说了什么
I told people you were a whore.
我告诉别人你是妓女
I'm sorry.
对不起
Alright? Are we good?
可以了吗？
Tell her why.
告诉她为什么
I can tell her.
我可以告诉她
Because he asked you a question.
因为他问你一个问题
He wanted to be lovers.
他想做你的男朋友
But you didn't even give him a reply.
但是你甚至都没有给他回复
That made Afsin really mad.
那让阿夫辛发疯了
Because he's so dumb he doesn't realize that you've given up talking.
因为他太笨，他没有意识到你已经不屑跟他说话了
Hand it over.
给我
- I don't have it on me. - Where, then?
-我没带在身上 -那在哪里？
Come with me.
跟我来
Selim, go ahead to the car. I'll be right there.
塞利姆，上车  我马上就来
- Where are you going? - I'll be right there.
-你要去哪里？-我马上就来
Out for a ride, boys?
出去兜风吗？
- What are you doing here? - Nothing. Just standing here.
-你在这里做什么？-什么都没做  只是站在这里
Oh,
哦，
Vural, you'd know what to do.
乌拉尔，你会知道该怎么办
I have a gun.
我有枪
A really old one.
一把很古老的枪
Where can I take it to be repaired?
我拿到哪里可以修呢?
Why do you have a gun?
你带枪干嘛？
- I don't know. I just do. - What use would you have for it?
-我不知道  就是带了  -你用枪做什么呢？
I want to chase away the flies.
我想赶走苍蝇
Why would flies flee from a gun?
苍蝇为什么要从枪下逃走?
You do this.
你这样做
Nesrin,
内斯林
pointing a gun and shooting it are two very different things.
用枪指着和开枪是两码事
I've pointed a gun at someone only once in my life.
我这辈子只拿枪指过别人一次
It was my ex-husband.
那人是我的前夫
And I pulled my trigger.
然后我扣动扳机
But this is really old. It doesn't work, anyway.
但这枪真的很旧  反正不能用
I can show you. See?
我可以给你看  看到了吗?
It worked.
能用
Pity. I shot your tyre.
真可惜，我打中了你的轮胎
Better the tyre than one of you, though, right?
打中轮胎要比打中你们中的一个更好，对吧？
Alright, then.
那好吧
By the way, Ufuk...
顺便说一下   乌福克
Ask your mom over to my place for tea. Don't forget to tell her.
叫你妈妈到我家喝茶  别忘了告诉她
What have you done, Nesrin?
内斯林，你做了什么？
Don't you realize how dangerous they are?
你不知道有多危险吗？
Besides, where did you get that gun?
另外，你从哪儿拿到那把枪？
I went...
我去……
and talked to Sungur the pimp.
跟皮条客桑古尔谈了谈
I paid for it, too. So what?
我买来的，怎样？
You want me to just sit and watch while they threaten my husband?
你要我就这样看着他们威胁我的丈夫吗？
The real question is...
问题是
Where did you find that stone, Selim?
塞利姆，你在哪里找到那块石头？
It was really dark. Did you have to look long for it?
天很黑  你找了很久吗?
Or did you scramble to find it, to get a stone in yourself?
还是你自己抢来的？
Was that how it went?
那是怎么回事？
If you really did that,
如果你真的做了
then you're more dangerous than they are, Selim.
那你比他们更危险
Step aside.
靠边
Still no visitors.
仍然没有人拜访我
They must've forgotten about me.
他们一定忘了我
Don't be silly.
别傻了
Your daughter calls every day. She'd never forget about you.
你的女儿每天都在打电话  她永远不会忘记你
The shuttle was launched.
航天飞机发射了
The shuttle was launched but still no visitors.
航天飞机发射了，但仍然没有人来找我
They must've forgotten me here.
他们一定是忘了我
The shuttle was launched.
航天飞机发射了
Come on.
来吧
- Weren't you scared? - Just watch.
-你不怕吗？-看着
See the bloodstain?
看到血迹了吗？
The aquarium was busted, as well.
鱼缸也被打碎了
Suveyda. Come here.
苏薇达  过来
Isn't that Mehmet Yurtgil?
那不是穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔吗？
Point it at me.
指着我
That's it.
就这样
What did you do next?
接下来你做什么？
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
No way.
不可能吧
Right then and there?
就在那里？
Don't get too excited. We didn't record it.
别太兴奋  我们没有录制
Shit.
该死
Here you go. You can watch the rest of it later.
给你，你可以稍后看其他内容
You won't find the footage in there anywhere else.
在其他任何地方都找不到素材
We went to all the crime scenes.
我们去了所有犯罪现场
So? Did you find any clues?
那你找到任何线索了吗？
About who the guy might be, I mean.
我是说  凶手可能是谁
- That's not the point. - What is it, then?
-那不是重点  -那什么是重点？
Suveyda, show him.
苏薇达  给他看看
Nevra's cat.
内芙拉的猫
Cat cat psychopath.
猫猫精神变态
What is this?
这是什么？
Welcome to the fan club of Turkey's first legit serial killer.
欢迎来到土耳其首个合法的连环杀手粉丝俱乐部
We had to find a nickname for the guy. Like Jack the Ripper.
我们要先给杀手起个绰号，就像开膛手杰克
We wanted to find a nickname related to the stickers.
我们想找到一个与贴纸有关的绰号
- We decided to start calling him Stick. - Stick.
-我们最开始决定称他为贴纸男  -贴指男
That's good.
好啊
We wanted to call him Writer at first, but we decided it would be silly.
本来想称他为作家，但我们觉得很蠢
Then I thought about the cat costume.
然后我想到了猫服装
This is what we came up with.
这就是最终我们想出来的
- What are you doing? - Hold on.
-你在做什么？-别急
DOG SLAYER
狗杀手
- Here it is! - Holy fuck!
-就是它了  -卧槽！
That's a great name!
真是个好名字！
Suveyda didn't like it at all first. Killing dogs doesn't appeal to her.
苏薇达一开始就不喜欢  因为杀狗对她没有吸引力
But I explained to her that it had nothing to do with dogs.
但我向她解释说，这与狗无关
We all love dogs, right?
我们都爱狗，对吗？
But that's not the point. This is something else.
但不是重点  这是另外一回事
He's a cat. A cat that kills dogs.
他是猫  杀死狗的猫
The weak triumphing over the strong.
弱者胜过强者
It goes against everything we know. It goes against nature.
它违反了我们所知道的一切  违背了自然法则
I think that's awesome.
我觉得很棒
- I see. - We're almost there.
-我知道了-我们就快准备好了
Just some finishing touches on the website and we go live.
网站还有一些收尾的工作，然后我们就嫩上线了
What's missing?
还缺什么？
A forum asking a question: Whom would you like Dog Slayer to kill?
一个论坛的问题：你希望狗杀手杀死谁?
People will share on the forum whom they wish death on,
人们会在论坛上分享他们希望死亡的对象
and why they deserve to die.
以及为什么他们应该死
They will even vote on each other's victims.
他们甚至会投票给对方的受害者
A list will emerge.
一个死亡清单即将出现
Like a stock exchange but for prospective murder victims.
像证券交易所一样，但针对潜在的谋杀受害者
That's rad.
太棒了
Imagine Dog Slayer actually killing someone from that list.
想象一下杀是杀手真的杀死了名单上的某个人
Why not?
为什么不呢？
- Hold on. I'm almost done. - Sure.
-等一下  我快完成了  -当然
- Take the chair over there. - I'm fine standing.
-坐那边的椅子  -我站着就行
Have you ever heard about the village of Durucay?
你听说过杜鲁凯村吗？
I worked at the courthouse there for a while.
我在那儿的法院工作过一段时间
One day, our superiors told us we had to go to a mandatory seminar.
有一天，上司告诉我们，我们必须去参加强制性研讨会
Some Americans came and made a deal with the ministry.
一些美国人前来与该部达成协议
They were the ones holding the seminar.
他们是举行研讨会的人
Anyway...
总之……
I was working as a court clerk then. It's the most important job there.
那时候我是法院书记员，这是最重要的工作
You have to write each and every word down,
你必须写下每一句话，
never missing a single one.
永远不会漏掉任何一句
- I'll wash up and be right back. - What? Sure, sure.
-我会洗干净然后马上回来  -什么？好的
So we went to the seminar.
我们去了研讨会
They gave us these...
他们给我们发了这种……
These masks.
口罩
Stenomasks, they were called.
他们被称之为速记口罩
You speak into it. It's so sound-proofed that no one can hear what you're saying.
人们对着它说话非常的隔音，没人听见你在说什么
It's connected to a recorder that records everything you say.
它连接着一个录音机，录下你所说的一切
Anyway...
总之……
So they gave me one and I started using it.
他们给了我一个，我开始使用它
It was such a weird feeling, speaking and not having anyone hear you.
感觉很奇怪，说话时没有人听到你的声音
It was so impressive that I started seeing it in my dreams.
令人印象深刻，我开始在梦中看到它
For instance...
比方说
I'm in a crowded place in the dream.
我在梦中拥挤的地方
I speak and speak but no one can hear.
我会说话  但没人能听到
You know what happened a few days ago?
你知道几天前发生了什么吗？
I was waiting in line at the bank when a woman came to warn me.
我在银行排队等候时，一位女职员过来提醒我
She told me I was speaking to myself.
她说我是在自言自语
I was pretty shook up. Who knows what I'd told her.
我吓坏了  谁知道我跟她说了什么
- Would you like some tea? - No, thank you.
-要喝茶吗  -不，谢谢
It's funny how things change.
事情的变化很有趣
I used to be terrified that no one would hear what I said.
我曾经很害怕没有人会听到我说的话
Now, I'm terrified that they might.
现在，我很害怕他们可能会听到
I guess...
我猜……
That's life.
那就是人生
What's wrong with your car?
你的车怎么了？
My car's fine.
我的车很好
I'm the one with the problem.
我就是那个有问题的人
What have I done?
我做了什么？
I forgot to ask him where Ufuk lived.
我忘了问他乌福克住的地方
How am I supposed to find him now?
我现在应该怎么找到他？
Hello?
喂？
Hello? How do you answer this?
喂？这鬼东西怎么接啊？
How do you answer this?
怎么接啊？
You were so good at this stuff, Mebrure.
你曾经很擅长用这些东西，梅布鲁雷
You were so good at answering the phone and talking to the caller.
你很擅长接电话并和打电话的人交谈
I asked you to teach me how but you kept putting it off. Now look at me!
我让你教我怎么做，但是你一直拖着，现在你看我！
You went and left me, and here I am, all alone!
你走了，留下我一个人在这里!
What am I supposed to do now? Whom am I supposed to ask for help?
我现在该怎么办？我该找谁帮忙？
Am I supposed to ask them how to answer a phone?
我应该问他们如何接电话吗？
Won't they mock me?
他们不会嘲笑我吗？
An adult man who can't even answer a phone!
一个成年男人竟然不会接电话！
See what you did? I'm over here talking to myself!
看看你对我做了什么？我在这里自言自语！
He can't do anything! He can't even answer a phone!
他什么也做不了，甚至连电话都不会接！
I wouldn't be talking to myself if you were here.
如果你在这里我就不会自言自语了
That's what the woman at the bank said. I was talking to myself.
那是银行的女职员说的。我在自言自语
Yes, but no one will hear what I'm saying.
是的，但是没人会听到我在说什么
You don't hear what I'm saying.
你听不到我在说什么
You don't hear!
你听不到
No one listens! No one listens to me!
没有人听！没有人听我说！
No one!
没人！
- Good morning.
- 早上好  -早上好
- Have you been waiting long? - No. I just got here.
-等了很久吗 -没有，我刚到
Take me to the house.
带我去那房子
UFUK EXPECTING YOU FOR DINNER IN KAMBURA
乌福克：在坎布拉等你吃饭
You do hear me.
你听到了
You should've wished for something bigger.
你应该期望更大的目标
Just this morning, you said you wanted to see Kambura again,
就在今天早上，你说你想再看看坎布拉
and here we are, on our way there.
现在我们就在过去的路上
You're right.
是的
When you asked me to cancel all your meetings, I was concerned.
当你要求我取消所有会议时，我很担心
- Everything's alright, right? - Of course. Everything's alright.
-没事吧  -当然没事
I want to see an old friend.
我想见一个老朋友
We should have some fish. Our fish is unlike anywhere else's.
我们应该吃点鱼  那里的鱼与众不同
And some raki, as well.
再来些葡萄酒
You do drink, right?
你喝酒吧？
It doesn't really agree with me.
它真的不适合我
One glass of raki never hurt anyone.
一杯葡萄酒不会怎样的
I've seen much more implausible reports before.
我之前看过很多令人难以置信的报道
Reports declaring that a man shot from behind had killed himself.
报道称一名男子从背后开枪自杀
- Welcome to Kambura. - It's a nice place.
-欢迎来到坎布拉  -这是一个好地方
Like a fairy tale. Why don't you like it?
就像童话一样，你为什么不喜欢呢？
Here are the red riding hoods, and there are the wolves.
这里有小红帽和大灰狼
And mandatory happy endings no matter what comes to pass.
无论怎样都会有强制性的幸福结局
It's a fairy tale, alright. We just need to find the narrator.
这是童话，好吧，我们只需要找到一个讲故事的人
Selim or whomever it was that wrote that report.
塞利姆或撰写报告的人
Ufuk!
乌福克！
Ufuk, come and help me!
乌福克，过来帮帮我！
Ufuk, I'm talking to you!
乌福克，我在叫你！
- Let me finish my smoke. - Put it out!
-让我抽完烟  -把烟掐了！
Have you lost your mind! What are you doing!
你疯了吗！你在做什么！
What's one more scar?
还有什么伤疤?
Ufuk! Ufuk! Where are you going, son?
乌福克！乌福克！儿子，你要去哪里？
Has it been like this for ten years? Why don't they tear it down?
十年来一直这样吗？为什么不把它拆了？
I think they're so used to seeing it that they don't even notice it anymore.
我想他们已经习惯了，甚至都没有注意到它
You can't tear down something you don't notice.
你不能拆毁你根本没有注意到的东西
The people lost in the fire...
人们在大火中迷失了自我
Tayyar Kaymak, 49. His wife, Songul Kaymak, 41.
49岁的塔亚尔·凯马克和他41岁的妻子松古尔·凯马克
And their five children.
还有他们的五个孩子
Seven people, all living in this tiny house?
七个人都住在这间小房子里？
I read something in a novel once.
我曾经读过一部小说
"Man takes less and less space the poorer he gets," it said.
书上说：“人越穷，占用的空间就越少。”
The poorer you are, the smaller you can make yourself.
越穷，就越小
So that's why the richer people get, the more space they need.
这就是为什么富人需要更多的空间
Explains the gigantic houses.
解释了他们问什么有巨大的别墅
How old was the youngest child?
最小的孩子几岁？
Four months old.
四个月大
In such a tiny house.
在这么小的房子里
Could you go to sleep when you have a four-month-old here?
当你有一个四个月大的孩子时，你能睡着觉吗?
I don't remember what I did as a four-month-old.
我不记得我四个月大时做了什么
I'll tell you what you did. You cried nonstop.
你会不停地哭
So how come the report says
那报告怎么这样写
that they were presumed to have slept through the fire?
他们被推测在火灾中睡着了?
All of them.
全都睡着了
How's that possible? All seven of them, asleep.
那怎么可能呢？七个人都睡着了
I already told you.
我已经跟你说过
Whatever's in the report goes.
报告就是这样写的
Tayyar Kaymak had some priors, right?
塔亚尔·凯马克有一些前科，对吧？
Yes. Jailed twice, both times for burglary.
是的  两次入狱，两次都是入室盗窃
Burglary...
入室盗窃
If you were a thief...
如果你是小偷
would you be living in this place with six other people
你会和另外六个人住在这个地方吗
while also working the fields?
还在地里干活?
Never.
决不
I might start working the fields if I'd repented for my sins, though.
不过，如果我为自己的罪过忏悔，我可能会在田里干活。
Tayyar wasn't a thief.
塔亚尔不是小偷
Not a single one of the people who died in this house was a thief.
在这个房子里死去的人中没有一个是小偷
- So... - Ufuk.
-所以……-乌福克
Alright, Ufuk.
好的，乌福克
Where were you burnt?
你在哪里被烧伤的？
I was burnt here, as well.
我也时在这里被烧伤的
I was trying to save them.
我想救他们
Who started the fire?
谁扔的火把？
I did.
我扔的
I was standing right there.
我当时正站在那儿
Everything flared up in an instant. I was startled.
一切突然爆发了  我被吓了一跳
I thought they'd get out of the house after seeing the flames.
我以为他们看到火焰后会离开屋子
But no one get out. The fire was getting bigger.
但没人出门  火势越来越大
I could hear the screaming children inside.
我能听到里面的孩子在尖叫
I could hear the children's screams!
我能听到孩子们的尖叫声！
I ran to the door, but the door was chained and locked.
我跑到门口，但门被锁住了
I tried to break the chains, but I couldn't.
我试图打破锁链，但我做不到
I ran to the other window. It was shut, as well.
我跑到另一个窗口，但也被封锁了
I thought maybe...
我想也许
I couldn't get anyone out!
我无法把任何人救出来！
I shouted to the crowd! Help me, I said!
我向人群大喊！帮帮我！
Let's break the chains together! Somebody help me!
我们把锁链打开！来人帮帮我！
Nobody helped! Nobody broke the chains!
没有人帮助！没有人打开铁链！
Nobody came! Nobody helped me!
没人来！没人帮助我！
- Then... - Ufuk!
-然后……  -乌福克
Ufuk!
乌福克！
- Ufuk. - What?
-乌福克  -什么
Who chained the doors?
谁把门锁住了？
I asked them who did. They told me there were no chains.
我问他们是谁锁的  但他们告诉我没有锁链
I was supposedly...
我应该是
I was burnt while trying to rescue the family.
我在营救他们时被烧伤了
A falling beam hit me on the head.
落下的横梁击中了我的头
Ufuk, here's what we're going to do.
乌福克，我们接下来这样做
- Ufuk, we're going... - Arrest me!
-Ufuk，我们要……  -逮捕我！
- Sure, alright.
-当然可以  -逮捕我！
- Come with me. - Arrest me!
-跟我来  -逮捕我！
- Sure. Fine. - I killed those children. Arrest me!
-好的  -是我杀了那些孩子  快逮捕我！
- Sure. - Please!
-好的  -请！
- Let's talk for a bit. - My face was burnt here!
-让我们谈谈-我的脸就是在这里被烧伤了！
- Sure, come with me. - Arrest me, please arrest me!
-当然，跟我来  -逮捕我，请逮捕我！
- Sure, I will. - Arrest me! See my scars?
-当然，我会的  -逮捕我！看到我的伤疤了吗？
- Sure. - I burnt the house down!
-当然  -是我把房子烧毁了！
- I understand. - I killed those children.
-我知道  -我杀了那些孩子
- Alright, alright. - Please arrest me.
-好的  -请逮捕我
Look at that house! I'm the one who burnt it down!
看那所房子！我是烧毁它的人！
- I understand. - The children! I burnt it all down!
-我明白了  -还有孩子们！我把它全部烧掉了！
- The boy's talking. - Leave him be.
-他说了  -别管他了
Let him talk.
让他说吧
- You still haven't gotten married? - No.
-你还没结婚吗  -没有
Of course.
当然
You already have a wife, right?
你已经有老婆了吧？
- Kambura. - That's right.
-坎布拉  -是的
Why did you call me here, Cemil?
你为什么给我打电话，塞米尔？
What do you want from me?
你想从我这里得到什么？
What are you doing with that gun?
你用那把枪做什么？
Blowing out tyres.
打轮胎
I heard.
我听说了
I heard it all the way in Istanbul.
我在伊斯坦布尔就听说了
I'm sure it did.
当然了
Selim will be alright, Nesrin.
内斯林，塞利姆会没事的
No one's going to hurt him.
没有人会伤害他
All we ask...
我只是想问……
- Is that his imaginary remorse... - Imaginary?
-那是他想象中的悔恨……—想象中的?
Exactly.
正是
He should keep it to himself.
他应该保密的
Quietly.
悄悄的
Let's say you successfully shut Selim up.
假设你成功让塞利姆闭嘴了
What will you do with Ufuk?
你会对乌福克做什么？
How will you shut that poor boy up?
你怎么让那个可怜的男孩闭嘴？
Why would I shut him up?
我为什么要把他闭嘴？
He's talking as we speak.
在我们聊天的同时他正在说
Talking to whom, you may ask.
你可能会问他在跟谁说
He's talking to that beautiful daughter of yours.
他在跟你那个美丽的女儿说话
Nevra doesn't realize that Ufuk is a troubled man.
内芙拉没有意识到乌福克是个很麻烦的人
For years now, he's confessed to arson to every cop he ran across.
多年来，他对他遇到的每个警察都承认纵火
You should let Nevra know the next time you see her.
下次见到内芙拉时，你应该告诉她
He is a certified loon. He doesn't know what he's saying.
他是一个疯子  他根本不知道自己在说什么。
Don't you ever wonder what really happened?
你难道不想知道到底发生了什么吗？
- About? - The truth.
-关于什么？  -真相
No.
不想
So you don't want to know.
所以你根本不想知道
I'm loyal to my wife, Nesrin.
我忠于我的妻子  内斯林
You know what true loyalty is?
你知道什么是真正的忠诚吗？
Never questioning.
永不质疑
In other words, deceiving yourself.
换句话说，欺骗自己
Have you ever...
你有没有……
loved anyone so much that you'd never question anything?
像这样爱过什么人，你永远都不会质疑任何事情？
believed in something no matter what?
不论发生什么都会一直坚信某件事？
Of course not. Never.
当然没有，从没有过
I guess...
我猜……
you must've never had a family, Nesrin.
你一定从未拥有过家庭，内斯林
KAMBURA POLICE DEPARTMENT
坎布拉警察署
You didn't cuff me.
你没给我戴手铐
- You promised you'd arrest me. - Don't you realize the state he's in?
-你答应过要逮捕我  -你不知道他什么状态吗？
Let us talk to him and we will.
让我们跟他谈
Thank you for all your help.
谢谢你的帮助
Tell it from the beginning.
从最开始说起
- I already did. - Tell it again.
-我已经说过了  -再说一次
How many times do I need to tell it?
我需要说多少次？
I thought you were proper cops. I burnt the house down!
我以为你们是真正的警察  是我把房子烧毁了！
I killed all those people! What else is there to say?
我杀了他们！还有什么要说的？
It seems you won't do your job, either.
看来你也不会抓我的
I'm not telling you anything.
我什么都没告诉你
I'll keep telling it to myself.
我将会继续告诉自己
I'm so sick of this. I'm so sick of it.
我很讨厌这样  我很讨厌
I can do it myself. I don't need you.
我自己可以做  不需要你
Where do you think you're going?
你以为你要去哪里？
You're just standing there. You haven't even put me in cuffs!
你只是站在那儿  你甚至都没有把我戴上手铐！
Fuck you and your cuffs!
去尼玛的手铐！
You there! Look here! Come here! Quick!
你！这边！过来！快！
Give me that!
手铐给我！
Hold out your hands! Hold them out!
伸出双手，伸出双手！
There you go! There's your cuffs!
好了！现在你有手铐了！
Let me talk to him alone.
让我跟他单独谈谈
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
I'll be right outside. Yell if you need anything.
如果你需要什么，我就在门口
You were the one I was chasing that night, right?
你就是那天晚上我追的那个人，对吗？
Why did you want me to see it, Ufuk?
乌福克，你为什么要我看到它？
Why did you want the truth to come out after all these years?
过了这么多年，你为什么要现在说出真相？
After all these years?
过了这么多年？
I've been imploring the cops ever since the incident.
自事件发生以来我一直在恳求警察
Telling them that I did it. That they should arrest me.
告诉他们是我做的  他们应该逮捕我
I've been shouting it from the rooftops for ten years.
我已经说了十年
But no one will listen.
但是没人听
Then they leave.
然后他们离开这里
Others take their place.
其他人接替他们的位置
I tell them. They don't listen, either.
我告诉他们  他们也不听
I heard Nesrin's daughter had become a cop.
听说内斯林的女儿当了警察
I thought that maybe...
我以为
Maybe she'd listen to me.
也许她会听我的
But how was I supposed to find you?
但是我应该怎么找到你呢？
Then, one day, you appeared in Kambura.
然后，有一天你突然出现在坎布拉
Do you have any trash, Naz?
纳兹，你有垃圾吗？
Your door's unlocked.
你的门没锁
Naz?
纳兹？
Are you home? It's Seyit.
你在家里吗？我是斯易特
Who else was there with you on the night of the fire?
火灾当晚还有谁跟你在一起？
I don't remember.
我不记得了
But everyone was there. I'm sure of it.
但是我很确定所有人都在那里
Alright.
好的
If Tayyar Kaymak never stole anything,
如果塔亚尔·凯马克从未偷过任何东西
why did that crowd gather outside his house, aiming to kill him?
那为什么那群人聚集在他的房子外面，并且要杀死他？
Why else?
怎么会这样
Because they were gypsies.
因为他们是吉普赛人
Because they were gypsies?
因为他们是吉普赛人？
You're telling me that all those people, all those children...
你是在告诉我所有人，包括那些孩子
They were killed because they were Romani?
他们被杀是因为他们是罗马人？
- That's the only reason? - Yes. It's enough.
-那是唯一的原因吗？-是的
How do you know that? Who told you?
你怎么知道的？谁告诉你的？
Nobody told me.
没人告诉我
Nobody told me, because...
没人告诉我，因为
I remember it all too well.
我记得很清楚
I don't remember exactly who was there.
我不记得是谁
But I remember very well...
但我记得很清楚
what I said, what I shouted out as I was throwing that torch.
我说的是什么，我在扔那个火炬时大喊
What were you saying, Ufuk?
你在喊什么，乌福克？
"Fuck off out of Kambura!"
“滚出坎布拉！”
"Get out, you filthy gypsies!"
“滚出去，你们这些肮脏的吉普赛人！”
I TOLD NEVRA EVERYTHING BUT SHE WON'T BELIEVE ME.
我把一切都告诉了内芙拉，但她不相信我
Our beautiful apartment is going to be all over the news.
我们美丽的公寓将会上新闻
You demon. You're going to bring misfortune upon us.
你这个恶魔，你会给我们带来不幸
The newspaper told me
报纸上说
that I'd be getting paid for the tip. How much you think I'll get?
我可以获得情报的报酬  我能得到多少？
I'll give you the money.
我给你钱
Maybe he had a special friend. Maybe he did it.
他可能有一个特殊的朋友，可能是他做的
You think she was selling herself? What do you think?
你认为她在出卖身体吗？你怎么看？
I doubt she was selling herself.
我不认为她在出卖自己的身体
Unlike you.
不像你
Don't be like that. Go on, leave.
不要那样，走吧
- Let him go! - Let the poor boy go!
-让他走！-让可怜的男孩走！
Do you want us to come and get him?
你要我们冲进去找他吗？
- Huh? - My son!
-嗯 -我儿子
My son! Don't be scared. I won't leave you in there!
我的儿子！不要害怕  我不会把你留在那里！
I won't let anyone hurt you!
我不会让任何人伤害你！
Let me go!
让我走！
He's certified! Certified, I'm telling you! My son is sick!
他有诊断！我告诉你！我儿子病了！
Let him go! Son! Ufuk!
放开他！儿子！乌福克！
Ufuk!
乌福克！
He's certified!
他有诊断！
He really is certified.
他真的有诊断
States that he's in poor mental health. He can't be held liable.
声明他精神状况不佳  他不用承担任何责任
I tried telling you, but you wouldn't listen.
我试着告诉过你，但你不听
DIAGNOSIS: IN POOR MENTAL HEALTH
诊断：精神健康状况不佳
Sefa, listen to me carefully.
塞法  认真听我说
Keep your wits about you, and stay in the building.
保持警惕，待在楼里
I've sent you back-up. They'll be there soon.
我已经发给你一份备份  很快就会到
They'll get both you and the suspect out of there.
可以把你们和犯罪嫌疑人带出去
What?
什么？
I take all responsibility. Just bring the guy to me.
我承担所有责任  一定要把那个家伙带给我
- Go! - Understood, sir.
-去吧  -明白  长官
I think I've had enough.
我不喝了
Come on. You've had only one glass.
来吧  你只喝了一杯
Besides, it's really hard to drink too much in Kambura.
另外，在坎布拉喝酒真的很难
How was the meeting?
聚会怎么样？
- What? - How was your meeting?
-什么？-你的聚会怎么样？
Oh. Good, it was good.
哦，很好，很好
I met an old acquaintance, from back when your father was here.
我遇到了一个老相识，还是你父亲在这儿的时候认识的
Funny.
真有趣
You might know my father better than I do.
你可能比我更了解我的父亲
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Excuse me.
请原谅
Yes?
喂？
What?
什么？
Taking him to Istanbul?
带他去伊斯坦布尔？
Don't let them take him away. I don't care how.
无论如何不能让他们把他带走
Don't disappoint me.
别让我失望
Got it?
明白吗？
Everyone might know my father better than I do.
可能任何人都比我更了解我父亲
Yes...
好了……
Let him go! Let my son go!
放了他！让我儿子走！
Take him away! Take him away right now!
把他带走！马上带他走！
Feza? It's your turn.
费扎？轮到你了
Go on.
来吧
She has a beautiful voice. Wait 'til you hear it.
她有一副好嗓子  等着听
Go on, Feza. They're all listening.
来吧费扎  他们都在听
Here you go, Feza.
来吧  费扎
My head is foamy cloud.
我的头是泡沫状的云
My inside and outside is a sea.
我的内外都是大海
I'm a walnut tree in Gulhane Park.
我是古尔哈内公园的一棵核桃树
An old walnut tree. With long branches and pieces.
一棵老核桃树，长着树枝和碎片
Neither you are aware of this
你不知道
nor is the police.
警察也不知道
Whenever I recite that poem,
当我背诵这首诗时
I feel as I'm traveling into space.
我感觉我正在太空旅行
If you won't do it,
如果你不这样做
then I'll do it myself.
那我自己去做
I'll do it myself, alright. I'll show all of you.
我就自己做，我会证明给大家看
What's he doing in there?
他在里面做什么？
What's he up to?
他在干什么？
Ufuk!
乌福克
Ufuk, come on!
乌福克，出来吧
Shit.
该死！
Shit, shit, shit!
该死！，该死，该死！
What are you doing, just standing there, you dumbass?
你在干什么，怎么搞的，笨蛋？
Attention all units, I repeat:
所有单位请注意，我重复一遍：
The suspect is 1.79 tall and weighs 70 kilos.
犯罪嫌疑人身高179体重70公斤
He has distinctive burn marks on his face. His name is Ufuk Terazi.
他的脸上有明显的烧伤痕迹。他的名字叫乌福克·泰拉齐
- Clear. - Where could he have run to?
-没看到他 -他会去哪里？
- Check his home. - Where?
-去他家看看  -在哪里？
We should check his home.
我们应该去检查他的家
What's going on here?
这里发生了什么？
We don't have time for this.
没时间跟你废话
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？这是怎么回事？
Get out of our way.
离开这
- What do they want? - They want the kid, sir.
-他们想要什么？-他们要乌福克，长官
Hello there.
你好啊
- Stay back. Don't come any closer. - Sure, I won't.
-不要靠近我  -当然，我不会
It all ends here.
一切到此为止
You can't change my mind. I'm going to do it.
你不能改变我的主意
- I won't interfere. As you were. - Who are you?
-我不会干涉你  -你是谁？
- I'm just going to need the knife back. - What knife?
-我只想要回小刀  -什么刀？
- It was you? - Yes.
-刚刚那是你吗？-是的
- How did you know I'd be there? - I'm from Kambura, after all.
-你怎么知道我会去那里的？-毕竟我也来自坎布拉
We all know about that place. Escapers Central, you might call it.
大家都知道那个地方，你可以称之为越狱中心
Tevfik made his jailbreak there.
陶菲克曾在那个地方越狱
Everybody knows about it. They used to tell it like a fairy tale.
大家都知道  他们过去常常把它讲得像童话故事一样。
They must've told it to you, as well, huh?
他们也一定告诉过你，对吧？
I've never seen you before.
我从没见过你
Are you from Kambura?
你来自坎布拉吗？
In actual fact, Tevfik had that place built.
实际上，陶菲克建了那个地方
When he heard he was going to be transported
当他听说他要被转运到
to a prison in Istanbul, he called his men.
伊斯坦布尔的监狱时，他召集他的手下
Told them to construct a public bathroom on the highway.
告诉他们在高速公路上建造一个公共厕所
He'd ask the cops to stop there and run out the window.
他要警察在那里停下，然后他从窗户逃跑
The Can, they used to call it.
他们曾经称它为罐子
The Can.
罐子
Escape Central, as it later became known.
后来越狱中心渐渐被人们所熟知
How many years it must've been...
已经过去好多年了啊……
What do you want from me? Why did you help me?
你想从我这里得到什么？为什么要帮助我？
You texted your brother Umut telling him you were going to kill yourself.
你给你的弟弟乌穆特发了短信，告诉他你将要自杀
What was that you said?
你说什么？
"The woman cop is back in Kambura."
“女警察回到坎布拉”
I'm going to tell them everything.
我要告诉他们一切
"Either they jail me or I kill myself."
“他们要么抓我入狱，要么我自杀”
- How do you know about my text to Umut? - So I... Let me speak.
-你怎么知道我发给乌穆特的短信？-所以我……让我说完
Let me speak. I'm trying to tell you a story.
让我说完  我想告诉你一个故事
I saw them taking you away. I saw the crowd outside,
我看到他们把你带走  我看到外面的人群
telling them to let you go, telling them you're certified.
让警察放了你，告诉警察说你有诊断
I decided to wait in Escape Central. You never know, right?
我就决定在越狱中心等待你  世事难料，对吧？
How do you know about my text to Umut?
你怎么知道我发给乌穆特的信息？
Where is he? Is Umut here as well?
他在哪里？乌穆特也在这里吗？
No, son. Umut isn't here.
不，孩子  乌穆特不在这
- He's the one who sent you. - You could say that.
-是他让你来的  -你可以这么说
- So you know Umut? - Do I know him? Of course!
-所以你认识Umut吗？-我认识他吗？当然认识！
I know Umut. I know Seyfi.
我认识乌穆特  我也认识塞菲
All of Kambura knows you.
坎布拉的所有人都认识你们
Everybody used to love you.
每个人曾经都很爱你们
"Look at the triplets!" they'd say.
他们会说“快看，是三胞胎！”
I don't want to keep you much longer. Please get back to what you were doing.
我不想耽搁你太久  请你继续
I'll just be standing here.
我就只是站在这里
- Can I have the knife back, please? - Take it.
-请把刀还给我  -给你
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
He isn't here! Clear the road!
他不在这里！离开这里！
Clear the road! Ufuk ran away!
离开这里！乌福克逃跑了！
Clear the road so we can find him!
离开这里，方便我们找他！
We aren't going anywhere.
我们哪都不会去
We aren't going anywhere without Ufuk. Where is he?
没有乌福克我们哪都不去  他在哪里？
He's in the car, I know it! Let's overwhelm them and get him!
他在车上，我就知道！让他们不知所措，把他救出来！
Let's go.
我们走吧
Are they launching fireworks or something?
他们是在放烟花吗？
- Would you like some help, son? - Don't come any closer. Stay right there.
-你需要帮忙吗？孩子？-别靠近了
It's funny.
很有趣
I went to see a play the other day.
前几天我去看话剧
There was a scene that resembled this.
有一个类似于这个的场景
Not exactly, but close.
不完全相同，但很接近
I didn't find it believable at first,
一开始我觉得不可信
but I think they might've had a point.
但我现在认为他们说的有点道理
They said that conscience resembles the gut.
他们说良心很像内心
And the gut resembles conscience.
内脏就像良心
If you want it emptied, you have to be the one to do it.
如果你想让它空出来，你就必须自杀
Funny. See...
很有趣  你看……
I prepared this for you.
我为你准备了这个
To stick on your forehead.
贴在额头上
But since you're going to be the one to do it,
但是既然你将要自杀了
I wouldn't want to disrespect you.
我不想不尊重你
I wouldn't want to get between you and your conscience.
我不想介于你和你的良心之间
That's why I won't.
那就是我不会干涉你的原因
Go on.
继续
I wonder which of us is the crazier one. Leave me alone.
我想知道我们中谁是最疯狂的  走开！
- Would you like some help? - Stay right there!
-你需要帮助吗？-别过来！
Sure. But don't tarry.
当然可以，但别拖延了
The cops are looking for you. They might be here soon.
警察正在找你  他们可能很快就会来
Make it quick. Raise yourself. Just like this, see?
快点  把自己吊起来，就像这样，懂吗？
Not like that. Get on your tippy-toes.
不是那样的，小心点
That's it!
对了！
Let yourself go!
松手把！
Kill yourself and be done with it. No more pangs of conscience, Ufuk.
结束自己的生命吧  不再有良心的痛苦  乌福克
Go on, don't be scared.
继续，不要害怕
Go on!
继续！
Where are you?
哪去了？
It's funny.
真有趣
This is exactly how I taught my daughter to swim.
这正是我教我女儿游泳的方法
We were in Erdek.
我们在埃尔德克
She was on the pontoon. I was in the water.
她在船上  我在水里
I kept telling her to jump.
我让她跳下来
She refused to do it.
她不跳
I told her I was right there, there was nothing to be scared of.
我告诉她我就在那里，没有什么可害怕的
Come on, come to papa.
来吧，到爸爸这来
Let yourself go.
放自己走
Come on in.
来吧
That's it! That was some jump.
就是这样！
Zuhal wouldn't jump.
祖哈尔不会跳
She just froze.
她只是呆在那里
My little girl wouldn't trust her father.
我的小女儿不相信她的父亲
She was wise beyond her years.
她拥有她的年龄不应拥有的智慧
DOG SLAYER
狗杀手